Reinaldo Pared

+1(809) 986-4192 | reinaldopared@gmail.com | Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic

SUMMARY

IT Analyst with 10+ years of experience in maintaining company infrastructures and user systems. Highly effective at providing personal and remote support. Results-oriented and self-directed team player with an unsurpassed work ethic and energetic personality.

SKILLS

- Technical: Python, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Go, Bash, GitLab/GitHub, Vault, CI/CD, JavaScript, Terraform, Kubernetes, Docker, Jenkins, Ansible, Prometheus, New Relic, Grafana, ArgoCD, AWS, Heroku, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, System Administrator, Cloud Technology, BitDefender Gravity Zone, Agile Methodology, Back-End Web Development, Front-End Web Development, Full-Stack Web Development, Microsoft Office, VS Code, Windows, Mac OS, Linux.
- Professional:Issue Resolution, Computer Repair, Strong Adaptability, Resource Allocation, Problem-Solving, Time Management, Attention to Detail, Hardware Understanding, Technical Support, Supporting Projects, Technical Troubleshooting, Call Center Operations, Software Upgrades, Customer Support Needs Assessment, Equipment Repair, Team Collaboration, Decision-Making, Team Management, Analytical, Good Work Ethic.
- Language: Fluent Spanish and English.

EDUCATION

- 2023 Certificates: Scientific Computing with Python, Free Code Camp.
- 2022 Certificate: Responsive Web Design, Free Code Camp.
- 2014 Bachelor's Degree in System and Computers Engineering, Universidad APEC.

EXPERIENCE

IT Analyst, Visionary Solutions Inc., Santo Domingo, DR

April 2022 - Present

- Increased sales by 15% by identifying and targeting new customer segments.
- Designed, implemented, and maintained IT systems.
- Improved employee productivity by 15% through the implementation of a new help desk system.
- Conducted a user satisfaction survey, identified areas for improvement, resulting in a 25% increase in overall user satisfaction with the IT systems.
- Developed and implemented a new monitoring system, reducing response time to system issues by 70% and improving system uptime by 15%.

IT System Administrator, **Energía Alternativa de Petróleo**, Santo Domingo, DR

May 2010 - November 2019

- Conducted vulnerability assessments and implemented security controls, including IDS/IPS and antivirus software.
- Improved server response time by 10% through optimization of server resources and workload balancing.
- Deployed security patches and updates in a timely manner, resulting in a 50% reduction in security incidents and breaches.
- Managed and maintained an IT assets inventory system, resulting in a 15% reduction in lost or misplaced equipment and a 20% decrease in unnecessary equipment purchases.
- Provided technical support to end-users, resulting in a 40% decrease in support tickets and a 90% satisfaction rate.

IT Assistant, Instituto Nacional de Aguas Potables y Alcantarillados, Santo Domingo, DR

February 2007 - May 2010

- Kept project teams on-task with proactive control of budgets, schedules, and scopes, resulting in a 20% increase in project completion rates within the allocated budget and schedule.
- Assessed the performance of equipment and network infrastructure, resulting in a 15% increase in system reliability and a 10% reduction in downtime.
- Implemented proactive improvements in line with company standards, resulting in a 12% increase in equipment and network infrastructure efficiency.
- Inspected equipment and read order sheets to prepare for delivery to users, ensuring 100% accuracy in equipment and software delivery.
- Attended technical conferences and seminars to maintain knowledge of hardware and software, resulting in the adoption of new technologies that increased system efficiency by 8%.